<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-10-11T12:25:47+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Sean</title><subtitle>Ph.D | Quantitative Analyst</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Technical Strategies (Commodity Future)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Technical-Strategies/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Technical Strategies (Commodity Future)" /><published>2017-10-11T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-10-11T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Technical-Strategies</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Technical-Strategies/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;technical-analysis&quot;&gt;Technical Analysis&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most techincal analysis strategies focus on trend following, and a smaller part on contrarian. Currently, we mainly focus on trend following.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The recognition of a trend starts from a breakout. Usually there are two rails, upper and lower. The upward break of the upper rail means the start of up trend, and the downward break of the lower rail means the start of down trend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The famous &lt;a href=&quot;http://bigpicture.typepad.com/comments/files/turtlerules.pdf&quot;&gt;turtle rules&lt;/a&gt; are relying on the breaks, however, the more important part of the turtle rules is the distribution on positions. Products with high risk (large standard deviation in the past period) have lower weigths in the portfolio, and those with low risk have larger weights. This is actually the same with the Risk-Parity concept. How to calculate risk is another interesting problem, but for now, we only use the standard deviation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;dualthrust&quot;&gt;DualThrust&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A simple introduction can be found here &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quantconnect.com/tutorials/dual-thrust-trading-algorithm/&quot;&gt;Dual Thrust Trading Algorithm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;low-frequency-rails-daily-bar&quot;&gt;Low Frequency Rails (daily bar)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Upper rail: Open + Interval (determined by past High, Low, Close)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lower rail: Open - Interval (determined by past High, Low, Close)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;high-frequency-rails-1min-bar&quot;&gt;High Frequency Rails (1min bar)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DualThrust does not have high frequency rails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;back-test-result&quot;&gt;Back Test Result&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/DualThrust.png&quot; alt=&quot;Figure&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;dynamicbreakout&quot;&gt;DynamicBreakOut&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quantconnect.com/tutorials/dynamic-breakout-ii-strategy/&quot;&gt;Dynamic Break Out&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;low-frequency-rails-daily-bar-1&quot;&gt;Low Frequency Rails (daily bar)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Upper rail: Bollinger Band Upper Rail&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lower rail: Bollinger Band Lower Rail&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;high-frequency-rails-1min-bar-1&quot;&gt;High Frequency Rails (1min bar)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Upper rail: moving average of daily high&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lower rail: moving average of daily low&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;back-test-result-1&quot;&gt;Back Test Result&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/DynamicBreakOut.png&quot; alt=&quot;Figure&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;keltner&quot;&gt;Keltner&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thebalance.com/how-to-day-with-trade-keltner-channels-4051613&quot;&gt;Keltner Strategy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;low-frequency-rails-daily-bar-2&quot;&gt;Low Frequency Rails (daily bar)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No low frequency rails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;high-frequency-rails-1min-bar-2&quot;&gt;High Frequency Rails (1min bar)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Upper rail: moving average of close (1min) + ATR (1min)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lower rail: moving average of close (1min) - ATR (1min)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;back-test-result-2&quot;&gt;Back Test Result&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/Keltner.png&quot; alt=&quot;Figure&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;dochian&quot;&gt;Dochian&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://admiralmarkets.com/education/articles/forex-indicators/what-everyone-should-know-about-the-donchian-channel-indicator&quot;&gt;Dochian Strategy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;low-frequency-rails-daily-bar-3&quot;&gt;Low Frequency Rails (daily bar)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No low frequency rails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;high-frequency-rails-1min-bar-3&quot;&gt;High Frequency Rails (1min bar)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Upper rail: moving average of high (1min)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lower rail: moving average of low (1min)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;back-test-result-3&quot;&gt;Back Test Result&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/Dochian.png&quot; alt=&quot;Figure&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The strategies are relying on a lot of parameters defining the rails and intervals. Thus, overfitting may exists among them. Trend following is the most successful strategy in the past two century &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1404.3274&quot;&gt;Two centuries of trend following&lt;/a&gt;, the trend recognition deserves more exploration.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Technical Analysis Most techincal analysis strategies focus on trend following, and a smaller part on contrarian. Currently, we mainly focus on trend following.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Time Series Carry (Commodity Future)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Time-Series-Carry/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Time Series Carry (Commodity Future)" /><published>2017-10-10T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-10-10T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Time-Series-Carry</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Time-Series-Carry/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;time-series-carry&quot;&gt;Time Series Carry&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shrinking/enlarging of the carry return of a product also contains a trend to be captured. 
For contango products (near month is lower than deferred month), the shrinking carry return means the deferred month price is converging to the near month, thus a short position on dominant contract is preferred.
For backwardation products (near month is higher than deferred month), the shrinking carry return means the deferred month price is converging to the near month, thus a long position on dominant contract is preferred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;back-test-result&quot;&gt;Back Test Result&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The strategy is tested on all the products trading in the three Commodity Future Markets in China, including SHFE, DCE, CZCE, between Jan 1st 2005 and Aug 1st 2017. Trading cost is set at 3%% either for buy or sell, and no leverage is used. The potential risk free return is not included.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/TSC.png&quot; alt=&quot;Figure&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;known-problems&quot;&gt;Known Problems&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;path-dependency&quot;&gt;Path Dependency&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In implementation, this idea is characterized by several parameters, as listed below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the threshold of shrinking/noise.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the lookback period to calculate the shrinking of the carry return&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the threshold of the carry return to determine contango / backwardation.
Potential overfitting exists in backtesting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;future-works&quot;&gt;Future works&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to calculate the carry return. a) between the near month and the deferred month; b) between the near month and the dominant contract; c) between the dominant contract and the sub-dominant contract.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use moving average of the carry return, or compound carry return.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conflict-with-inter-temporal-arbitrage&quot;&gt;Conflict with Inter Temporal Arbitrage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Essentially, this strategy is like the Inter Temporal Arbitrage&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Time Series Carry The shrinking/enlarging of the carry return of a product also contains a trend to be captured. For contango products (near month is lower than deferred month), the shrinking carry return means the deferred month price is converging to the near month, thus a short position on dominant contract is preferred. For backwardation products (near month is higher than deferred month), the shrinking carry return means the deferred month price is converging to the near month, thus a long position on dominant contract is preferred.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Portfolio of Stock and CTA</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Portfolio/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Portfolio of Stock and CTA" /><published>2017-10-10T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-10-10T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Portfolio</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Portfolio/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;risk-parity-determine-the-strategys-weight&quot;&gt;Risk-Parity: determine the strategy’s weight&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The weight of a product’s position is determined by its standard deviation’s reciprocal. More academic resources can be found in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dailyalts.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/Risk-Parity-and-Diversification.pdf&quot;&gt;Qian2005&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For better cash management, the total weight is always constant, and the individual risk is used to determine the relative importance in the portfolio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;component-of-different-strategies&quot;&gt;Component of different strategies&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using risk-parity to determine weights, we can get a portfolio value for each strategy, such as the Time Series Momentum (TSM), Cross Sectional Momentum (XSM), Time Series Carry (TSC), Cross Sectional Carry (XSC). These strategies are for the commodities. 
Also, using the French-Fama Three-Factor Model, we can get an alpha portfolio in the stock market (STOCK).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/Port.png&quot; alt=&quot;Figure&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The alpha portfolio is constructed using the Eugene-Fama three factor model, exposing to the Price to Book Value and the Non Restricted Cap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;correlation-coefficients-of-different-strategies&quot;&gt;correlation coefficients of different strategies&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;known-problems&quot;&gt;Known Problems&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-distribute-the-weights-to-different-products&quot;&gt;How to distribute the weights to different products&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the lookback period for calculating the product’s risk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the method to calculate the product’s risk. a) standard deviation; b) exponential weighted moving average of standard deviation; c) other risk measures.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;how to determine the total weight of the portfolio. If all the products are volatile, then holding more cash is a better option.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Risk-Parity: determine the strategy’s weight The weight of a product’s position is determined by its standard deviation’s reciprocal. More academic resources can be found in Qian2005</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Model Review</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Model-Review/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Model Review" /><published>2017-10-10T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-10-10T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Model-Review</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Model-Review/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-is-model-review&quot;&gt;What is Model Review&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any strategy is dependent on parameters. Constant parameters are preferred. However, the parameters are usually changing. We define the process to tune the parameters as “Model Review”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although this process is to tune parameters, it needs new parameters itself:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the lookback period to calculate what is the best parameter, NMonthLookBack&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the period to conduct model review, NMonthModelReview&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example: for Time Series Momentum, we have parameters NDayTrain, NDayTest, NDayShift, NWeekStart to review. The best set of parameters is determined on its performance in the past NMonthLookBack, and the model review process will be conducted NMonthModelReview later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-is-the-best-nmonthlookback-nmonthmodelreview&quot;&gt;What is the best (NMonthLookBack, NMonthModelReview)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each (NMonthLookBack, NMonthModelReview), we have 10 value series with different review start date. Among them, the one with mininmum CR (worst) is selected as the score of this (NMonthLookBack, NMonthModelReview), which means we care the worst performance of (NMonthLookBack, NMonthModelReview). Of course, the (NMonthLookBack, NMonthModelReview) with the best worst-case performance is used, and its worst-case value series is as the Model Review version performance of the strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;known-problems&quot;&gt;Known problems&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-path-dependency&quot;&gt;The path dependency&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The path dependency is only partially solved by use 10 different review start dates. Actually, a more reasonable method to determine the review start dates is also necessary&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-tune-nmonthlookback-nmonthmodelreview&quot;&gt;How to tune (NMonthLookBack, NMonthModelReview)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process of tuning parameter is always relying on new parmeter, and this is infinite loop. To solve this, we review the NMonthModelReview and NMonthLookBack every year, and this is fixed.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">What is Model Review Any strategy is dependent on parameters. Constant parameters are preferred. However, the parameters are usually changing. We define the process to tune the parameters as “Model Review”.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Cross Sectional Carry Strategy (Commodity Future)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Cross-Sectional-Carry/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cross Sectional Carry Strategy (Commodity Future)" /><published>2017-10-10T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-10-10T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Cross-Sectional-Carry</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Cross-Sectional-Carry/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;carry-strategy&quot;&gt;Carry Strategy&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The currency carry trade is a strategy in which an investor sells a certain currency with a relatively low interest rate and uses the funds to buy a different currency yielding a higher interest rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although there is no interest in a commodity future contract, the discout rate plays the role. A commodity contract that is now traded at discount (with high discount rate), is equivalent with a currency with high interest rate. Assuming the the price of actuals is stable, then the price of the commodity future traded at discount rate will converge to that of the actual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;back-test-result&quot;&gt;Back Test Result&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The strategy is tested on all the products trading in the three Commodity Future Markets in China, including SHFE, DCE, CZCE, between Jan 1st 2005 and Aug 1st 2017. Trading cost is set at 3%% either for buy or sell, and the leverage is 250%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/XSC.png&quot; alt=&quot;Figure&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;known-problems&quot;&gt;Known Problems&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;path-dependency&quot;&gt;Path Dependency&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once entering the market, the position will be held for a period, which means there is a period (between a week to several months, depending on the strategy parameters) when no trade happens (this strategy is different from the conventionalstrategies like DualThurst, RBreak). The final performance of the strategy is affected by the starting date of test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although there is no perfect solution on this, some statistical features are found to mitigate such dependeces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another solution is to divide all the positions into N divisions (N is the days to hold the position), and adjust position every day on one division.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;trading-on-friday&quot;&gt;Trading on Friday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The performance of the strategy is partially affected by the day of week. Usually, Friday is the best day to trade. It is a statistical phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;trading-in-third-week&quot;&gt;Trading in Third Week&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is mostly due to deliving setting. Deliverying happens in the 3rd Friday of each month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conflict-with-the-momentum&quot;&gt;Conflict with the Momentum&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are times when a contract is traded at discount, while this product (including the dominant contract) is dropping. The momentum of the contract price affects the decision to follow the smart carry strategy.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Carry Strategy The currency carry trade is a strategy in which an investor sells a certain currency with a relatively low interest rate and uses the funds to buy a different currency yielding a higher interest rate.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Time Series Momentum (Commodity Future)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Time-Series-Momentum/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Time Series Momentum (Commodity Future)" /><published>2017-08-27T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-08-27T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Time-Series-Momentum</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Time-Series-Momentum/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;time-series-momentum&quot;&gt;Time Series Momentum&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More academic resources can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://scholar.google.com/scholar?hl=en&amp;amp;q=time+series+momentum&amp;amp;btnG=&amp;amp;as_sdt=1%2C5&amp;amp;as_sdtp=&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although not a securet for a long time, following market move has been profitable in the past century&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0304405X11002613&quot;&gt;Moskowitz2011&lt;/a&gt;. Different trend following strategies are only different at the criterion of the start/end of a trend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;back-test-result&quot;&gt;Back Test Result&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The strategy is tested on all the products trading in the three Commodity Future Markets in China, including SHFE, DCE, CZCE, between Jan 1st 2005 and Aug 1st 2017. Trading cost is set at 3%% either for buy or sell, and no leverage is used. The potential risk free return is not included.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/TSM.png&quot; alt=&quot;Figure&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;known-problems&quot;&gt;Known Problems&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;path-dependency&quot;&gt;Path Dependency&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once entering the market, the position will be held for a period, which means there is a period (between a week to several months, depending on the strategy parameters) when no trade happens (this strategy is different from the conventionalstrategies like DualThurst, RBreak). The final performance of the strategy is affected by the starting date of test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although there is no perfect solution on this, some statistical features are found to mitigate such dependeces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another solution is to divide all the positions into N divisions (N is the days to hold the position), and adjust position every day on one division.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;drop-of-performance-in-recent-years&quot;&gt;Drop of Performance in Recent Years&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunatelly, this simple Time Series Momentum strategy brings lower return and higher volatility recently. This can be partially attributed to the popularity of automatic trading in recent years. Simplly following the market may be a risky behavior in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Time Series Momentum More academic resources can be found here</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Adaptive Filter Strategy (Commodity Future)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Adaptive-Filter-Strategy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Adaptive Filter Strategy (Commodity Future)" /><published>2017-08-27T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-08-27T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Adaptive-Filter-Strategy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Adaptive-Filter-Strategy/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;trend-from-a-frequency-domain-perspective&quot;&gt;Trend from a Frequency Domain Perspective&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5 day Moving Average is equivalent with a low pass fitler with coefficients b = [0.2, 0.2, 0.2, 0.2, 0.2] and a = 1. 
The volatility is relatively high frequency (from day to day), when compared with the price move on a 5 day range. The trend is mostly hidden in the low-frequency area in the frequency domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the efforts to recognize the trend of price movement is actually searching for the informative low frequency components in the frequency domain. Shedding the communicaition techniques on the strategy field, we can leverage the filter design knowledge on our tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;filters&quot;&gt;Filters&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of frequency response, filters can be classified into low pass filter, high pass filter, band pass filter, band stop filter. Because trend is usually hidden in the low frequency domain, low pass filter (LP) and band pass filter (BP) are used in our tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digital filters can be classfied into two types: IIR and FIR. 
IIR has short latency, but it is not stable (output is feedbacked to intput). 
FIR has long latency, but it is stable. 
For now, FIR is used to extract the low frequency domain trend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;back-test-result&quot;&gt;Back Test Result&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The strategy is tested on all the products trading in the three Commodity Future Markets in China, including SHFE, DCE, CZCE, between Jan 1st 2005 and Aug 1st 2017. Trading cost is set at 3%% either for buy or sell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/FD.png&quot; alt=&quot;Figure&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;known-problems&quot;&gt;Known Problems&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;latency-of-the-filter&quot;&gt;Latency of the Filter&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us use the 5 day Moving Average line again. The average price we found on Day 5 is actually corresponding to the trend of the 3 day, the 2 day latency is the obastacle of using the filter techniques. However, we can never know the real trend on Day 5, because it is relying on the Day 3, Day 4, Day 5, Day 6 (Future), Day 7(Future) data.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Trend from a Frequency Domain Perspective 5 day Moving Average is equivalent with a low pass fitler with coefficients b = [0.2, 0.2, 0.2, 0.2, 0.2] and a = 1. The volatility is relatively high frequency (from day to day), when compared with the price move on a 5 day range. The trend is mostly hidden in the low-frequency area in the frequency domain.</summary></entry></feed>